export interface Flashcard {
  id: string;
  front: string;
  back: string;
  lesson: string;
}

export const defaultFlashcards: Flashcard[] = [
  {
    id: "1",
    front: "Why thylakoid membranes contain many types of pigments?",
    back: "To absorb light at wider range of wavelengths, to maximize light absorption hence photosynthesis",
    lesson: "Repeated",
  },
  {
    id: "2",
    front: "Why plants need to convert energy to ATP?",
    back: "Because ATP is the energy currency in all organisms including plants, and light energy cannot be used directly, and ATP is needed to convert GP -> GALP",
    lesson: "Repeated",
  },
  {
    id: "3",
    front: "Explain role of light energy",
    back: "To excite & release e- in reaction center chlorophyll in photosystems, so they can be used in photophosphorylation, and for photolysis of water to replace e- lost for formation of NADPH, to produce ATP & NADPH for light-indep stage",
    lesson: "Highly Repeated",
  },
  {
    id: "4",
    front: "Differentiate products of cyclic and non-cyclic Phot...?",
    back: "Cyclic produces ATP only, Non-Cyclic produces ATP + NADPH",
    lesson: "Important",
  },
  {
    id: "5",
    front: "From where do C,H,O come in Sugar?",
    back: "C & O from CO2, H from Water, *remember O in H2O is 'excreted'",
    lesson: "Repeated",
  },
  {
    id: "6",
    front: "How is GALP converted to Protein?",
    back: "By forming Hexose like Glucose, then Glucose is combined with NO3- ions from soil to make Amino Acids, AND also Glucose is used to produce ATP which is required in protein synthesis.",
    lesson: "Important",
  },
  {
    id: "7",
    front: "Why is 'Low-Lipid content', and 'high in Antioxidants' good?",
    back: "It reduces risk of heart disease",
    lesson: "6-Markers",
  },
  {
    id: "8",
    front: "Why is high protein and high carb good?",
    back: "Protein for growth & repair, carbs as source of energy",
    lesson: "6-Markers",
  },
  {
    id: "9",
    front: "What is the unit for NPP?",
    back: "kJ/m-2/year-1 (KiloJoules per metre squared per year)",
    lesson: "Common",
  },
  {
    id: "10",
    front: "Formula for NPP",
    back: "NPP = GPP - R",
    lesson: "Easy",
  },
  {
    id: "11",
    front: "Why theres no fourth/fifth trophic level?",
    back: "Energy is lost between levels, so no enough energy to sustain a 4th/5th level",
    lesson: "Repeated",
  },
  {
    id: "12",
    front: "Role of Micro-organisms in Carbon cycle",
    back: "Break down organic matter with hydrolytic enzymes [eg...] then respire and release CO2 to atmosphere which is used in photosyn. later by plants.",
    lesson: "Highly Repeated",
  },
  {
    id: "13",
    front: "When is something 'sustainable'?",
    back: "When it can be maintained to next gens without running out AND its not harmful to the env.",
    lesson: "Common",
  },
  {
    id: "14",
    front: "How to prove two organisms are related?",
    back: "Extract DNA samples from blood/hair/etc... and amplify with PCR, then run on Gel e. and compare number of similarities in bands",
    lesson: "Highly Repeated",
  },
  {
    id: "15",
    front: "Characterestics of Pioneer species?",
    back: "Fast life cycle and wide dispersal, low req of minerals and shade, withstand harsh env conditions",
    lesson: "Tricky",
  },
  {
    id: "16",
    front: "Why Succession occurs in stages?",
    back: "Habitat needs to be improved before it can contain an organism, eg. improving soil, so an organism appears AFTER the improvement, and improves it further for next organism",
    lesson: "Tricky",
  },
  {
    id: "17",
    front: "Evolution",
    back: "ALWAYS Mention 9: Natural selection, Polygenic + variation, Selection pressure, Mutation, Adv allele, Reason its adv, Allele freq in gene pool, Survive + Reproduce, Pass over many gens",
    lesson: "6-Markers",
  },
  {
    id: "18",
    front: "Finding age of a tree",
    back: "Each 1 year 1 new ring formed, thickness will depend on env conditions that yr, match many samples and count overlapping rings only once",
    lesson: "Important",
  },
  {
    id: "19",
    front: "Growth rate of a tree",
    back: "Height of tree / number of rings to get height increase per year",
    lesson: "Tricky",
  },
  {
    id: "20",
    front:
      "Why scientists think Micro-organisms will be able to break plastic?",
    back: "They already break organic matter in carbon cycle so already produce enzymes, and they mutate often so mutation can occur leading to breakdown of plastics",
    lesson: "Tricky",
  },
  {
    id: "21",
    front: "Which type of radiation is trapped by greenhouse gases?",
    back: "UV passes and infrared is trapped",
    lesson: "Important",
  },
  {
    id: "22",
    front: "What are two enzymes HIV has?",
    back: "Integrase & Reverse Transcriptase",
    lesson: "Easy",
  },
  {
    id: "23",
    front: "Why combine drugs?",
    back: "To increase effectiveness, if one drug doesnt penetrate cell other will, and if pathogen becomes resistant to one drug other drug will destroy it",
    lesson: "Tricky",
  },
  {
    id: "24",
    front: "Why Antibiotics affect bacteria but not humans?",
    back: "Bacteria are Prokaryotes, humans are Eukaryotes",
    lesson: "Repeated",
  },
  {
    id: "25",
    front: "What to tell patient when prescribing ABs?",
    back: "Finish full course, course length, dosage, side effects, warnings, do not share",
    lesson: "Repeated",
  },
  {
    id: "26",
    front: "Whats role of Gut/Skin Flora?",
    back: "Prevent growth of pathogens, by competing for space & nutrients, gut flora release vitamin-K, all flora release lactic acid, reducing acidity, and releasing antimicrobials",
    lesson: "Highly Repeated",
  },
  {
    id: "27",
    front: "Some Aseptic Techniques",
    back: "Beside Bunsen burner, minimize time of culture exposure, sterilize equipment",
    lesson: "Highly Repeated",
  },
  {
    id: "28",
    front: "Why work next to Bunsen burner",
    back: "To create updraft and move Bacteria in air away so it doesnt fall in culture and contaminate it",
    lesson: "Important",
  },
  {
    id: "29",
    front: "Why Aseptic Techniques",
    back: "To prevent contamination of culture, and affecting results (eg. over/underestimating bacteria number, growth, competition) and prevent infecting humans",
    lesson: "Highly Repeated",
  },
  {
    id: "30",
    front: "Why incubate at xºC for y hrs?",
    back: "xºC for high enzyme activity but not denaturing, y hrs to give enough time for growth (until micro-org is visible), and enough time for antimicrobial to have effect",
    lesson: "Repeated",
  },
  {
    id: "31",
    front: "Role of Viral Glycoproteins",
    back: "To attach to host cells by binding to specific receptors, or act as a way to evade host immune system, eg. Glycan shielding, Decoys, Antigenic Variation",
    lesson: "Tricky",
  },
  {
    id: "32",
    front: "How Skin prevents infections other than Flora?",
    back: "Keratin is a physical barrier, Sebum increases acidity.",
    lesson: "Important",
  },
  {
    id: "33",
    front: "Why is pain important in inflammation?",
    back: "To alert person thet theyre injured, so they can prevent putting stress on injured place, and give more care like rest, ice, elevation.",
    lesson: "Tricky",
  },
  {
    id: "34",
    front: "Difference between circular DNA & linear DNA",
    back: "Linear DNA has Histones, one-less phospho. bond, unbound phosphate group., 3' & 5' ends",
    lesson: "Tricky",
  },
  {
    id: "36",
    front: "PCR Requirements",
    back: "DPN-DB: DNA sample, Primers, (free, mono-)Nucleotides, DNA Polymerase, Buffer",
    lesson: "Important",
  },
  {
    id: "37",
    front: "PCR Temperatures",
    back: "DAE - Denature 94ºC, Annealing 54ºC, Extension 72ºC",
    lesson: "Important",
  },
  {
    id: "38",
    front: "Whats a proper number of PCR cycles to get enough sample copies",
    back: "35 Cycles",
    lesson: "Important",
  },
  {
    id: "39",
    front: "How to get number of copies assuming 100% efficiency?",
    back: "2^n where n = number of cycles",
    lesson: "Tricky",
  },
  {
    id: "40",
    front: "How forensic entomology can tell if a corpse has been moved?",
    back: "Some insects only live in a specific habitst eg. underwater or indoors, so if non-native species was found then corpse was moved",
    lesson: "Tricky",
  },
  {
    id: "41",
    front: "Why would we cage a mammal corpse?",
    back: "To avoid eating of tissue by other animals",
    lesson: "Tricky",
  },
  {
    id: "42",
    front: "Speciation",
    back: "Allopatric (Area) or Sympatric (Same), isolation then different mutations, diff selection pressures, diff adv alleles diff changes in allele freq, reproductive isolation",
    lesson: "Repeated",
  },
  {
    id: "39",
    front: "How to get number of copies assuming 100% efficiency?",
    back: "2^n where n = number of cycles",
    lesson: "Tricky",
  },
  {
    id: "39",
    front: "How to get number of copies assuming 100% efficiency?",
    back: "2^n where n = number of cycles",
    lesson: "Tricky",
  },
  {
    id: "39",
    front: "How to get number of copies assuming 100% efficiency?",
    back: "2^n where n = number of cycles",
    lesson: "Tricky",
  },
  {
    id: "39",
    front: "How to get number of copies assuming 100% efficiency?",
    back: "2^n where n = number of cycles",
    lesson: "Tricky",
  },
  {
    id: "39",
    front: "How to get number of copies assuming 100% efficiency?",
    back: "2^n where n = number of cycles",
    lesson: "Tricky",
  },
  {
    id: "39",
    front: "How to get number of copies assuming 100% efficiency?",
    back: "2^n where n = number of cycles",
    lesson: "Tricky",
  },
  {
    id: "39",
    front: "How to get number of copies assuming 100% efficiency?",
    back: "2^n where n = number of cycles",
    lesson: "Tricky",
  },
  {
    id: "39",
    front: "How to get number of copies assuming 100% efficiency?",
    back: "2^n where n = number of cycles",
    lesson: "Tricky",
  },
  {
    id: "39",
    front: "How to get number of copies assuming 100% efficiency?",
    back: "2^n where n = number of cycles",
    lesson: "Tricky",
  },
  {
    id: "39",
    front: "How to get number of copies assuming 100% efficiency?",
    back: "2^n where n = number of cycles",
    lesson: "Tricky",
  },
  {
    id: "39",
    front: "How to get number of copies assuming 100% efficiency?",
    back: "2^n where n = number of cycles",
    lesson: "Tricky",
  },
  {
    id: "39",
    front: "How to get number of copies assuming 100% efficiency?",
    back: "2^n where n = number of cycles",
    lesson: "Tricky",
  },
  {
    id: "39",
    front: "How to get number of copies assuming 100% efficiency?",
    back: "2^n where n = number of cycles",
    lesson: "Tricky",
  },
  {
    id: "39",
    front: "How to get number of copies assuming 100% efficiency?",
    back: "2^n where n = number of cycles",
    lesson: "Tricky",
  },
];
